Gabriel Costa

gabrielcg@protonmail.com 087 605 1353 http://gcgoncalves.github.io http://linkedin.com/in/gcgoncalves

B.Sc. in Computer Science from Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul, elected the best Computer Science College in Brazil. Programming language agnostic, I have five years of experience developing on both the back and front-end of websites and web-based applications in environments ranging from startups to international companies.

Professional Experience:

DevOps Engineer at IBM
December/2020 – Present

Working under IBM WH team, provisioning and maintaining IKS toolchains.

Cloud Developter at IBM

December/2018 – December/2020

Working under IBM WCE team,
provisioning and maintaining IKS clusters.

Web Developter at IBM
June/2017 – December/2018
Working under IBM mySA team,
developing a SaaS CRM platorm.

Software Engineer at Azion
Technologies (CDN)
May/2016 – May 2017
Cloud platform for content delivery and

Cloud platform for content delivery and acceleration with global operations and more than 25 points of presence around the globe.

Software Engineer at Superplayer (Startup)

September/2015 – April/2016 Music streaming service with more than a million active users on the web, android and iOS.

- Creating and maintaining IKS pipelines for applications CI/CD.
- Developing bash scripts for automating the CI/CD process
- Development and maintenance of ansible playbooks for infrastructure management and monitoring.
- · Deploy and maintain IKS clusters.
- Develop a web dashboard for cluster management.
- · Unit Testing.
- Development and maintenance of a CRM used by IBM business partners.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Unit Testing and E2E Testing.
- Development and maintenance of components on the Azion CDN configuration software.
- Lead front end developer.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Test Driven Development and Domain Driven Development.
- Development and maintenance of components on the superplayer music player platform.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Data and results analysis.
- A/B Testing.

Intern at Pmweb (Digital Marketing Agency)

March/2014 – August/2015 Multiple times award winner digital marketing agency focused on the hospitality business.

- Development and maintenance of websites for hotels and resorts.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Email marketing development.
- Database management.

Intern at Sthima (Startup) April/2013 – February/2014

B2B web base CRM software development company targeting medium-sized enterprises.

- Development and maintenance of cloud-based CRM software.
- Responsible for the full stack (server-side application logic and front-end development).
- Minor CSS and JavaScript adjustments.
- Database management.

Education:

B.Sc. in Computer Science Universidade Federal do Rio Grande do Sul 2008 – 2015

Courses:

User Experience Design ESPM 2017 - 16 hours

Design Intro Valkiria IC 2014 - 16 hours

Skills:

- Programming logics.
- Front-end: HTML, JavaScript, CSS/Sass and frameworks such as AngularJs, ReactJs and Bootstrap.
- Back-end: Python, JavaScript (Node.js), C#/ASP.NET and PHP.
- Good understanding of RESTful services.
- Experience in SQL and NoSQL modeling and querying.
- Version control tools experience using Git and SVN.
- UX Design enthusiast.